Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Corporate Documentation, 1896-1988
The John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
J. Walter Thompson Company. Corporate Documentation 1896-1988
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
J. Walter Thompson Company.
55 Linear Feet 40000 Items
The J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT), founded in 1864, is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States.
Corporate Documentation primarily consists of minute books to the regular meetings of JWT's stockholders and Directors; administrative and finance records; and reports from JWT's subsidiaries, committees and other institutional bodies. Topics covered include annual assessments of agency performance; planning; by-laws; stock incentive plans and retirement plans; and efforts to standardize operational practices across the many offices of JWT. The collection also includes background information relative to annual meetings, and the anniversaries of various offices. The collection derives from the RG1 Record Group, Corporate Documentation and General Reference, created by the JWT Archives prior to the transfer of the archives to Duke University.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
However, access to some records is limited to photocopies of the original documents.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. There may be a 48-hour delay in obtaining these materials.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. Corporate Documentation collection was received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a transfer in 1987 with additions in subsequent years.
Collection Overview
Corporate Documentation primarily consists of minute books to the regular meetings of JWT's stockholders and Directors; administrative and finance records; and reports from JWT's subsidiaries, committees and other institutional bodies. Topics covered include annual assessments of agency performance; planning; by-laws; stock incentive plans and retirement plans; and efforts to standardize operational practices across the many offices of JWT. The collection also includes background information relative to annual meetings, and the anniversaries of various offices.
The collection derives from the RG1 record group, Corporate Documentation and General Reference, created by the JWT Archives prior to the transfer of the archives to Duke University.
Records have been arranged into five topical series: General Administration; Committees; JWT Group; International Offices; and Subsidiaries.
The General Administration Series consists of records relating to the Board of Directors, corporate by-laws, office anniversaries, and several types of financial records, including those pertaining to stock issue, the Profit-Sharing Trust, and employees' retirement trust accounts. The Committees Series includes background materials and minutes to the regular meetings of corporate committees. The JWT Group Series contains records generated during the period, beginning around 1980, when JWT reorganized its assets into a holding company, the JWT Group. The International Offices Series primarily consists of minutes to annual meetings held by JWT offices outside the United States. The Subsidiaries Series primarily consists of minutes to annual meetings, along with some incorporation documentation, of wholly or partially owned JWT subsidiary companies.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
J. Walter Thompson Company
J. Walter Thompson Company -- Management
Advertising agencies -- History
Advertising agencies -- Management
Advertising agencies -- United States -- History
Advertising agencies -- United States -- Management
By-laws -- United States
Corporations -- United States -- Accounting
Corporations -- United States -- Finance
Corporations -- United States -- History
Corporations -- United States -- Management
Employee stock options -- United States
Management committees
Organizational effectiveness
Pensions -- United States
Retirement -- united States -- Planning
Business records
Corporation records
Minute books
Minutes
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Contents of Collection
- General Administration, 1896-1988
  - Board of Directors
    - Background
      - 1953-1957 (Box GEN-BD1)
      - 1958-1959 (Box GEN-BD2)
      - 1960-1962 (Box GEN-BD3)
      - 1963-1965 May (Box GEN-BD4)
      - 1965 June-Dec. (Box GEN-BD5)
      - 1966-1968 June (Box GEN-BD6)
      - 1968 Sept.-1970 (Box GEN-BD7)
      - 1971-1972 (Box GEN-BD8)
      - 1973-1974 Nov. (Box GEN-BD9)
      - 1974 Dec.-1975 (Box GEN-BD10)
      - 1976 (Box GEN-BD11)
      - 1977-1978 (Box GEN-BD12)
      - 1979-1980 Apr. (Box GEN-BD13)
      - 1980 June-1981 May (Box GEN-BD14)
      - 1981 July-1982 Aug. (Box GEN-BD15)
      - 1982 Aug.-1983 Aug. (Box GEN-BD16)
    - Research reports, 1981 (Box GEN-BD17)
  - By-Laws
    - Binder, 1923-1972 (Box GEN-BY1)
  - Financial Records
    - $5mm Note Due, 1977 (Box GEN-FN1)
    - Price Waterhouse files
      - 1974 (Box GEN-FN2)
      - 1975 (Box GEN-FN3)
    - Public stock offering, 1969 (Box GEN-FN4)
  - Index Card Files
    - Charitable contributions, 1971-1977 (Box GEN-IX1)
    - Index to Board Minutes, 1907-1939 (Box GEN-IX2)
    - Indices to Executive Committee, Finance Committee, and Legal Department Annual Reports, 1938-1968 (Box GEN-IX3)
  - Office Anniversaries
    - 125th and 130th aniversaries of JWT, 1989, 1994 (Box GEN-OA1)
    - Argentina/Belgium/India/Venezuela, 1977-1984 (Box GEN-OA2)
    - Italy/Japan/Philippines, 1981-1986 (Box GEN-OA3)
    - Mexico, 1978, 1983 (Box GEN-OA4)
  - Profit-Sharing Trust
    - Meetings
      - 1942-1947, 1942-1964 (Box GEN-PS1)
        Includes correspondence 1942-1964
      - 1947 July-1959 Feb. (Box GEN-PS2)
      - 1959 Mar.-1966 Feb. (Box GEN-PS3)
      - 1966 Mar.-1969 May (Box GEN-PS4)
      - 1969 June-Dec. (Box GEN-PS5)
      - 1970 Jan.-July (Box GEN-PS6)
      - 1970 Sept.-1971 Feb. (Box GEN-PS7)
      - 1971 Apr.-Dec. (Box GEN-PS8)
      - 1972 Jan.-July (Box GEN-PS9)
      - 1972 Aug.-1973 Jan. (Box GEN-PS10)
      - 1973 Feb.-Aug. (Box GEN-PS11)
      - 1973 Sept.-1974 Apr. (Box GEN-PS12)
      - 1974 Apr.-1975 July (Box GEN-PS13)
  - Regional Directors Meetings
    - Minutes, 1980-1982 (Box GEN-RD1)
  - Stock Holder and Directors Meetings
    - Background
      - 1917-1938 (Box GEN-SD1)
      - 1939-1953 (Box GEN-SD2)
      - 1954-1965 (Box GEN-SD3)
      - 1966-1974 (Box GEN-SD4)
    - Minutes
      - 1896-1907 (Box GEN-SD5)
      - 1896-1950 (Box GEN-SD6)
        [Unbound materials including: Thompson Briggs Company, 1911; J. Walter Thompson Advertising Company, 1931-1936; New Jersey and New York incorporations]
      - 1917-1923 (Box GEN-SD7)
      - 1924-1925 (Box GEN-SD8)
      - 1925-1929 (Box GEN-SD9)
      - 1930-1933 (Box GEN-SD10)
      - 1934-1938 (Box GEN-SD11)
      - 1939-1942 (Box GEN-SD12)
      - 1943-1946 (Box GEN-SD13)
      - 1946-1951 (Box GEN-SD14)
      - 1952-1955 (Box GEN-SD15)
      - 1956-1960 (Box GEN-SD16)
      - 1961-1963 (Box GEN-SD17)
      - 1964-1965 (Box GEN-SD18)
      - 1965-1966 (Box GEN-SD19)
      - 1966-1967 (Box GEN-SD20)
      - 1968-1969 Jan. (Box GEN-SD21)
      - 1969 Apr. (Box GEN-SD22)
      - 1969 Apr. (2) (Box GEN-SD23)
      - 1969 June (Box GEN-SD24)
      - 1969-1970 (Box GEN-SD25)
      - 1970-1971 (Box GEN-SD26)
      - 1971-1972 (Box GEN-SD27)
      - 1972-1973 (Box GEN-SD28)
      - 1973 (Box GEN-SD29)
      - 1974 (Box GEN-SD30)
      - 1975 July (Box GEN-SD31)
      - 1976 Jan. (Box GEN-SD32)
      - 1976 Apr. (Box GEN-SD33)
      - 1977 Jan. (Box GEN-SD34)
      - 1977 June (Box GEN-SD35)
      - 1978 May (Box GEN-SD36)
      - 1978 Sept. (Box GEN-SD37)
    - Nancy Fitzpatrick Files (Unprocessed), 1978-1985 (Box GEN-SD38-SD41)
      [Nancy Fitzpatrick was Vice President and Assistant Secretary of JWT]
  - Stock Incentive Plan
    - Minutes
      - 1969-1976 (Box GEN-SI1)
      - 1973-1980 (Box GEN-SI2)
      - 1977-1980 (Box GEN-SI3)
  - U.S. Employee Retirement Trust
    - Background
      - 1976 May, 1977 Jan.-1987 Dec. (Box GEN-UR1)
      - 1979 Jan.-1980 Oct. (Box GEN-UR2)
      - 1980 Oct.-1982 Apr. (Box GEN-UR3)
      - 1982 Jan.-1983 june (Box GEN-UR4)
      - 1983 July-Oct. (Box GEN-UR5)
    - Minutes
      - 1975 Aug.-1976 Sept. (Box GEN-UR6)
      - 1976 Oct.-1977 Sept. (Box GEN-UR7)
      - 1977 Oct.-1978 Sept. (Box GEN-UR8)
      - 1978 Oct.-1979 Oct. (Box GEN-UR9)
      - 1980-1981 Jan. (Box GEN-UR10)
      - 1981 Mar.-Oct. (Box GEN-UR11)
      - 1982 Jan.-June (Box GEN-UR12)
      - 1982 July-Oct. (Box GEN-UR13)
      - 1983 Jan.-June (Box GEN-UR14)
      - 1983 July-1984 Oct. (Box GEN-UR15)
- Committees, 1919, 1946-1985
  - Audit Committee
    - Meetings, 1975-1980 (Box COM-AU1)
  - Compensation Committee
    - 1974-1983 (Box COM-CO1)
  - Corporate Committee
    - Minutes, 1982-1983 (Box COM-CR1)
  - Executive Committee
    - Background
      - 1964-1965 (Box COM-EX1)
      - 1965-1966 (Box COM-EX2)
      - 1967 (Box COM-EX3)
      - 1968-1969 (Box COM-EX4)
      - 1970-1971 (Box COM-EX5)
    - Minutes
      - 1973 June-1975 July (Box COM-EX6)
      - 1975 Sept.-1979 Oct. (Box COM-EX7)
      - 1979 Sept.-1980 June (Box COM-EX8)
  - Finance Committee
    - L.O. Lemon Files, 1946-1957 (Box COM-FI1)
      [Luther Orange Lemon (1900-1957) was Treasurer and Director of JWT]
    - Minutes
      - 1946-1948 (Box COM-FI2)
      - 1949-1950 (Box COM-FI3)
      - 1951-1952 (Box COM-FI4)
      - 1953-1956 (Box COM-FI5)
      - 1957-1959 (Box COM-FI6)
  - Loan Committee
    - Minutes, 1980-1983 (Box COM-LO1)
  - Operations Committee
    - Jack Cronin presentation, 1985 Sept. (Box COM-OP1)
      [John J. Cronin was President of the Toronto Office of JWT]
    - Meetings
      - 1980 Aug.-1982 July (Box COM-OP2)
      - 1982 Sept.-1983 Apr. (Box COM-OP3)
      - 1983 June-1984 Jan. (Box COM-OP4)
      - 1984 Jan.-1985 Mar. (Box COM-OP5)
      - 1985 Mar.-Dec. (Box COM-OP6)
    - Troutbeck Inn meetings
      - 1983 Aug.-Sept. (Box COM-OP7)
      - 1984 Sept. (Box COM-OP8)
  - Committee on Standardization
    [Primary task of the Committee on Standardization was to establish uniform practices across all JWT offices and operations]
    - Minutes (Originals: RESTRICTED--See Use Copies in Box COM-ST2), 1919 (Box COM-ST1)
    - Minutes (Use copies), 1919 (Box COM-ST2)
- JWT Group, 1980-1984
  - Audit Committee
    - Meetings, 1980-1983 (Box GRP-AU1)
  - Board of Directors
    - Background, 1980 June-1981 Dec. (Box GRP-BD1)
    - Meetings
      - 1982 Feb.-Mar. (Box GRP-BD2)
      - 1982 Apr.-1983 Mar. (Box GRP-BD3)
      - 1983 Apr.-Dec. (Box GRP-BD4)
      - 1984 Jan.-Aug. (Box GRP-BD5)
      - 1984 Sept.-Dec. (Box GRP-BD6)
  - Compensation Committee
    - Meetings, 1980-1983 (Box GRP-CO1)
  - Executive Committee
    - Background
      - 1984 Jan.-Aug. (Box GRP-EX1)
      - 1984 Sept.-Dec. (Box GRP-EX2)
    - Minutes
      - 1980 Aug.-1981 Dec. (Box GRP-EX3)
      - 1982 Feb.-May (Box GRP-EX4)
      - 1982 May-1983 Feb. (Box GRP-EX5)
      - 1983 Apr.-Dec. (Box GRP-EX6)
  - Stock Incentive Plan
    - Meetings, 1981-1983 (Box GRP-SI1)
- International Offices, 1929-1974
  - J. Walter Thompson de Mexico, S.A.
    - Minutes
      - 1944-1961 (Box INT-MX1)
      - 1960-1967 (Box INT-MX2)
      - 1967-1973 (Box INT-MX3)
  - J. Walter Thompson do Brasil
    - Minutes
      - 1929-1936 (Box INT-BR1)
      - 1937-1950 (Box INT-BR2)
      - 1951-1962 (Box INT-BR3)
      - 1962-1964 (Box INT-BR4)
  - J. Walter Thompson Ltd. (Canada)
    - Minutes
      - 1930-1937 (Box INT-CA1)
      - 1938-1946 (Box INT-CA2)
      - 1947-1953 (Box INT-CA3)
      - 1954-1958 (Box INT-CA4)
      - 1959-1963 (Box INT-CA5)
      - 1964-1966 (Box INT-CA6)
      - 1967-1970 (Box INT-CA7)
      - 1971-1974 (Box INT-CA8)
  - JWT Australia/Belgium/England
    - Minutes, 1956-1969 (Box INT-VA1)
  - JWT France/Italy/India
    - Minutes, 1957-1972 (Box INT-VA2)
- Subsidiaries, 1930-1983
  - Ctizens Education Aid Foundation
    - Minutes, 1956-1957, 1965 (Box SUB-CE1)
  - Electronics and Alloys, Inc. (formerly JWTS Company)
    - Minutes
      - 1961-1968 (Box SUB-EL1)
      - 1967-1968 (Box SUB-EL2)
      - 1968-1976 (Box SUB-EL3)
  - Interlease Corporation
    - Minutes, 1965-1979 (Box SUB-IN1)
  - J. Walter Thompson Advertising Corporation
    - Incorporation documents, 1931-1941 (Box SUB-JA1)
  - J. Walter Thompson Insurance, Ltd.
    - Review Committee, 1983 Jan.-Oct. (Box SUB-JI1)
  - J. Walter Thompson International Corporation
    - Incorporation documents, 1930, 1940 (Box SUB-JT1)
  - Norby Productions, Inc.
    - Minutes, 1954-1971 (Box SUB-NP1)
  - Northeast Indiana Motors, Inc.
    - Minutes, 1968-1979 (Box SUB-NT1)
  - Puerto Rican-American Insurance Corporation
    - Minutes, 1970-1974 (Box SUB-PR1)
      Includes minutes and annual reports
  - Various Other Subsidiaries
    - Minutes, 1957-1979 (Box SUB-VA1)
      Includes Agency Art Associates; Channel 3 Workshop; Diogenes Marketing Research; Ficho & Corley, Inc.